Class of 1909 Records, 1905-1975
Smith College Archives
Class of 1909 Records
1905-1975
Smith College. Class of 1909.
RG 80 UUID:8616d212-8ee8-400b-a3cc-5ea8d22191d5
19 boxes (13.1 linear ft.)
Smith College Archives Northampton, MA
This collection is in 19 boxes and contains photographs, invitations, songs, newspaper clippings, and other memorabilia from the commencement and reunions of the Class of 1909.
The Class of 1909 was the thirty-first entering class and the thirty-first graduating class of Smith College.
The Class of 1909 records, 1905-1975, contain materials describing the history and activities of the Class of 1909, including materials from commencement, reunions, senior dramatics, and other important events. Types of materials include photographs, invitations, songs, newspaper clippings, Class Secretary's records, and other memorabilia.
Individual biographical files are also available, and often include photographs, photo albums, newspaper clippings, letters and correspondences, and class notes.
Information on Use
Terms of Access and Use
The records are open for research according to the regulations of the Smith College Archives without any additional restrictions.
History of the Collection
The Class of 1909 Records were created by the students and donated to the College Archives.
- Baccalaureate Service 1909 (Box 1745, Folder 1)
- Commencement 1909 (Box 1745, Folder 2)
- Commencement-Music 1909 (Box 1745, Folder 3)
- Commencement-Photographs 1909 (Box 1745, Folder 4)
- Commencement Speaker 1909 (Box 1745, Folder 5)
- Freshman Frolic 1905 (Box 1745, Folder 6)
- Freshman Grind 1905 (Box 1745, Folder 7)
- Freshman Handbook 1905-1906 (Box 1745, Folder 8)
- Freshman Reception 1905 (Box 1745, Folder 9)
- Groups 1905-1909 (Box 1745, Folder 10)
- Ivy Day 1909 (Box 1745, Folder 11)
- Ivy Day-Photographs 1909 (Box 1745, Folder 12)
- Junior Frolic 1908 (Box 1745, Folder 13)
- Junior Prom 1908 (Box 1745, Folder 14)
- Junior Prom-Garden Party 1908 (Box 1745, Folder 15)
- Junior Ushers 1908 (Box 1745, Folder 16)
- Class Letters 1922-1975 (Box 1745, Folder 17)
- Memorabilia undated (Box 1745, Folder 18)
- Last Sing 1909 (Box 1745, Folder 19)
- Class Secretary's Correspondence 1972-1973 (Box 1745, Folder 20)
- Class Supper 1909 (Box 1745, Folder 21)
- Alumnae Quarterly Clippings 1944-1951 (Box 1745, Folder 22)
- Alumnae Quarterly Clippings 1952-1973 (Box 1745, Folder 23)
- Reunions 1910 (Box 1745, Folder 24)
- Reunions 1912 (Box 1745, Folder 25)
- Reunions 1914 (Box 1745, Folder 26)
- Reunions 1919 (Box 1745, Folder 27)
- Reunions 1924 (Box 1745, Folder 28)
- Reunion Book 1924 (Box 1745, Folder 29)
- Reunions 1929 (Box 1745, Folder 30)
- Reunions 1934 (Box 1745, Folder 31)
- Reunions 1939 (Box 1746, Folder 1)
- Reunions 1944 (Box 1746, Folder 2)
- Reunions 1949 (Box 1746, Folder 3)
- Reunions 1954 (Box 1746, Folder 4)
- Reunions 1959 (Box 1746, Folder 5)
- Reunions 1964 (Box 1746, Folder 6)
- Reunions 1969 (Box 1746, Folder 7)
- Reunions 1974 (Box 1746, Folder 8)
- Class Secretary's Records-A-B (Box 1746, Folder 9)
- Class Secretary's Records-C-D (Box 1746, Folder 10)
- Class Secretary's Records-E-G (Box 1746, Folder 11)
- Class Secretary's Records-H-J (Box 1746, Folder 12)
- Class Secretary's Records-K-L (Box 1746, Folder 13)
- Class Secretary's Records-M (Box 1746, Folder 14)
- Class Secretary's Records-N-R (Box 1746, Folder 15)
- Class Secretary's Records-S (Box 1746, Folder 16)
- Class Secretary's Records-T-W (Box 1746, Folder 17)
- Class Secretary's Notes II-K-R (Box 1746, Folder 18)
- Class Secretary's Notes II-S-Z (Box 1746, Folder 19)
- Non-Graduates: Class Secretary's Notes (Box 1746, Folder 20)
- Senior Dramatics 1909 (Box 1747)
  - Senior Dramatics: Business Manager's Report 1909 (Box 1747)
  - Senior Dramatics: Photographs 1909 (Box 1747)
  - Senior Dramatics: Photographs 1909 (Box 1747)
  - Senior Dramatics: Photographs 1909 (Box 1747)
- Senior Reception 1909 (Box 1747)
- Songs undated (Box 1747)
- Banner (Box OV)